

# Profile

Software engineer with 6+ years of experience in Android development. I have worked on numerous freelance projects and built and published many apps on my own. I can adapt to both self-starting and collaborative environments while focusing on high-quality results under strict deadlines. Sincere about starting my new journey and tackling android challenges for the years to come.

# Education

**Android Kotlin Developer, Android Development, Udacity** February 2022 — May 2022

Taught by **Google Engineers**, learning the latest and **best practice** Android development techniques from MVVM architecture to dependency injection and testing.

Worked with more than 19 projects and built 5 on my own.

## Front End Web Development, treehouse

January 2020 — December 2020

Engineer's degree Data Engineering, School of Information Sciences (ESI), Rabat, Morocco

January 2016 — October 2020

Math / Physics, Ibn Tahir High School, Errachidia, Morocco January 2014 — December 2016

Mathematics BAC, SIJILMASSA high school, Errachidia, Morocco January 2011 — December 2014

### Courses

Java Android Development, Treehouse

February 2016 — May 2016

**TOEIC - English** 

# Employment History

Android Engineer at BidSys, Rabat, Morocco

July 2020 — June 2022

Freelance Android Developer at UpWork

August 2016 — May 2022

# Relevant internships

 ${\bf Mobile\ Developer\ at\ LE\ DIGIMENTAL\ LIMITED, Casablanca, Morocco}$ 

January 2020 — July 2020

#### **Details**

ERRACHIDIA Morocco +212 681564731 kerbalsc@gmail.com

#### Links

Linkedin GitHub Portfolio

#### **Skills**

Android Development

Android SDK

Git

Kotlin

Android Studio

**Automated Testing** 

Test-driven development

Firebase

SOL

Continuous Integration

Agile and Scrum

# **★** Attended Events

DevFest, Google Developer Groups (GDG), Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
December 2019

# **★** Relevant Projects

# Who is using my WIfi?

Android (native) app lets users discover and keep track of devices connected to the network. The app received a total of **6+ Million downloads** on Play Store.

https://gitlab.com/ilyasKerbal/wumw

### **PostureWise**

Android & IOS app built using Flutter. The app helps fix bad posture by providing short, simple exercises arranged in 30 days program.

https://gitlab.com/ilyasKerbal/posturewise

# **Political Preparedness**

An application that provides civic data intended to provide educational opportunities to the U.S. electorate using data provided by the Google Civic Information API.

## **Location Reminder**

TODO list app with location reminders that remind the user to do something when the user is at a specific location.